1500 slaves. 353,260,000 royal subjects. Warlords. Concubines. And
2 wives. He was the loneliest boy in the world.
The Last Emperor is a drama, history film directed by Bernardo Bertolucci.
A dramatic history of Pu Yi, the last of the Emperors of China, from his lofty birth and brief reign in the Forbidden City, the object of worship by half a billion people; through his
abdication, his decline and dissolute lifestyle; his exploitation by the invading Japanese, and finally to his obscure existence as just another peasant worker in the People's Republic.
Pu Yi (Adult), played by John Lone.
Wan Jung, played by Joan Chen.
Reginald Johnston (R.J.), played by Peter O'Toole.
The Governor, played by Ruocheng Ying.
Chen Pao Shen, played by Victor Wong Chi-Keung.
Big Li, played by Dennis Dun.
The Last Emperor (Italian: L'ultimo imperatore) is a 1987 epic biographical
drama film about the life of Puyi, the last Emperor of China.
It is directed by Bernardo Bertolucci from a screenplay he co-wrote with Mark Peploe, which was
adapted from Puyi's 1964 autobiography, and independently produced by Jeremy Thomas.
The film depicts Puyi's life from his ascent to the throne as an infant to his
imprisonment and political rehabilitation by the Chinese Communist Party.
It stars John Lone in the eponymous role, with Peter O'Toole, Joan Chen, Ruocheng Ying, Victor Wong, Dennis Dun,
Vivian Wu, Lisa Lu, and Ryuichi Sakamoto (who also composed the film score with David Byrne and Cong Su).
It was the first Western feature film authorised by the People's
Republic of China to film in the Forbidden City in Beijing.
The Last Emperor premiered at the 1987 Tokyo International Film Festival, and was
released in the United States by Columbia Pictures on November 18.
It earned widespread positive reviews from critics
and was also a commercial success.
At the 60th Academy Awards, it won all nine Oscars it was nominated for,
including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay.
It also won several other accolades, including three BAFTA Awards, four Golden Globe Awards,
nine David di Donatello Awards, and a Grammy Award for its musical score.
The film was converted into 3D and shown in the Cannes
Classics section at the 2013 Cannes Film Festival.
The film explores themes of suicide, experiment, china, isolation, buddhism.
The tone is emotional.